Preliminary guide to the Elizabeth "Betita" Sutherland Martínez papers M1854
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- 21. Miscellaneous
  - Letter-promotion, New youth intro, Cover/letters (Box 142, Folder 3)
  - From the field. The darker side of glory. A second reading of experience. "Memoirs of the 1960's" Evaluation notebook (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Job applications, Community College apps, Freelance editing work, Cal State Hayward (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Graphics, El Salvador, Corporate logos from Joel, In our image, Portfolio promo (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Power structure graphics, Claudius-> Negatives cartoons, attachments (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Designing Typeface, Bible Graphics, Production Materials, Graphics groups, Ideas of organization, Graphics by the Artist (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Mexico DCGC logos, etc. DCGC-unused card ideas-images and text, with freedom in their eyes: a photo-essay, Angola, Reagan comics (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Colored paper, Images for expos, Daycare/education (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Post cards, newsclippings, An Early Settler, fliers, paper, etc. (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - ESM books, clippings, school work, etc. (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Howard-1960's incl. Palante, Date Book 1963 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - 1964-Miguel Grinberg, 1965 Cy Harvey etc., The Nation 1963-64, Letters-Andras Sander (Hungary) 1964-1972, Letters to "The Nation" (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Walt Delegull, 1967-1970 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - The Bogalusa story, NACLA newsletter, Swarthmore College: an informal history by Richard J. Walton (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Promo samples, Design principles, Design-forms; workshops, China General (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Design samples/ideas, Hasting school communicating newsletters, Keep Strong volume 4 number 6, Community training and development project, Newsclippings (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Paper samples (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Unsorted drafts, research, etc. (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Line of March (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Poster (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - General facts, Legal general (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Logos book and other uses. (part 1) (Box 15, Folders 5-6)
  - Books for children super market, Mini expos (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Couples and faces, Women international women day, Book for children: hospital (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Editorial guidelines, Fall, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Bio information (Box 137, Folder 1)
- 22. Newsclippings
  - Clippings, etc. kept by Betita During War Years, 1940s (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, brochures, etc. Not SNCC, 1964-1971 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Newsclippings (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Communist newsclippings, Communists within the Labor movement (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Unsorted newsclippings (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Newsclippings on books of the 60's (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 23. Daily planners & address books
  - Planners, 1986, 1987 (Box 163, Folder 3)
  - Planners, 1984, 1987 (Box 163, Folder 2)
  - Planner, 1983 (Box 163, Folder 1)
  - Planner, 1982 (Box 162, Folder 4)
  - Planner, 1973-1975 (Box 162, Folder 3)
  - Address Book (Box 48, Folder 8)
- 24. Schooling, Swarthmore
  - Penn., Mushroom workers, Swarthmore, 2000-05-28 (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - Bethesda High School, 1942 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Halcyon, 1946 Swarthmore College (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Halcyon, 1947 Swarthmore College (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Swarthmore College, The Organizer (Box 66, Folder 3)
- 25. Personal/Family/Finance
  Also includes some non-profit/foundation financial material.
  - Key documents + poems, Betita childhood (Box 164, Folder 2)
  - IRS federal taxes (Box 124, Folder 1, Box 123, Folders 4-5)
  - Bank statement, 2000-2002 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Russel A Rosensteel CPA, Peace and dignity, Financial reports, Akonadi, 501 letters, Moisa and Associates, ADM-Associates Arminda Montoya (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Betita personal documents, cards, notes and others (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Personal Photos-New Mexico, Beverley Axelrod (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Chevy Chase House (part 2), ESM Legal Documents (birth certificates, etc.) (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Family tree. Last trip home-1985. Chevy Chase house. (part 1) (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - CDS NO, Tana. Paid Bills, 1992-1993 (Box 51, Folders 2-3)
  - Notebook, Mother #1-3 (Box 48, Folders 5-7)
  - taxes (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - taxes, expenses (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - banking (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - taxes (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Annuity checks, Funeral expenses, RPM-1989 taxes, 1990 taxes (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Death certificates, Gov't bonds, Annuity death benefits (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Mother Legal, RPM-friends (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Lawyers and accountants, Will-Transition, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Betita + Tessa receipts/loan (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Mother Bab. Medical/Psych history, 1981-1984 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Medical, 1984-1987 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - RPM-Medical history, Parklawn Cemetery, Sacramento, 1996 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Einstein, RPM Medical, Rounsville care center, Medicare forms (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Ruth Martinez (includes biographies) (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - 1988-89 Guardian report, 1987-88 guardianship (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Guardian appointment, Guardian Report '89-90, Guardianship-termination (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Medical 1987-89, Gifts from MGM (trpm), M. G Martinez (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - House: Takoma Park house (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Guardian commission, storage, lawyers/accountants, 1984-1987 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Elizabeth Martinez, Guardian for Ruth Martinez, 1985-86 annual accounting file copy, Guardian Report 1984-85 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Police Attack-Legal documents (Box 43, Folder 4, Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Current Personal Letters (Box 43, Folders 1-3)
  - Real Women Have Curves, Tessa plays, "Land" 1992,Tessa-La Feria de la amnistia, Tessa "homework" "once removed," Tessa's play (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - V. Vermont, Tessa+ Roadsters, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 6)